Finding Aid for Center for Conflict Resolution (University of Michigan) records, 1952-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for Conflict Resolution (University of Michigan) records
1952-1972
University of Michigan. Center for Research on Conflict Resolution.
8773 Bimu C536 2
An interdisciplinary institution at the University of Michigan that supported social science research in the field of conflict resolution or "peace research," the Center was founded in 1959 by scholars associated The Journal of Conflict Resolution. The Center closed in 1971. Records include administrative files, correspondence, research files, publications and publicity files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
13 linear feet
Transferred from the Center for Research on Conflict Resolution (Donor # 8706) in March, 1998. The records also include material received from John Stevens (Donor # 4666 ). Additional material was received in 2011.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Center for Research on Conflict Resolution was an interdisciplinary institution that supported social science research in the field of conflict resolution or "peace research." It was founded in 1959 and closed in 1971. The idea for such a center grew out of The Journal of Conflict Resolution, whose editorial offices resided at the University of Michigan. The Journal was founded in 1957. Its inaugural editorial argued for a new emphasis on social science research on conflict resolution. "(T)he most important practical problem facing the human race today," the editorial contended,"...is the prevention of global war." To make intellectual progress towards solving this problem, "the study of international relations must be made an interdisciplinary enterprise, drawing its discourse from all the social sciences...." In fulfillment of this proscription, the Journal's editorial board included scholars from many disciplines, most notably Robert Angell from sociology, Kenneth Boulding from economics, and Irwin Katz from psychology.
The year following the establishment of the Journal, these same scholars began discussing the establishment of an interdisciplinary center to pursue the same objective as the Journal. Interdisciplinary study was well regarded in this period, and the university had already established several interdisciplinary centers, such as the Center for Japanese Studies. After months of discussion and searching for funding, the University of Michigan Regents established the Center for Research on Conflict Resolution in June 1959. The establishment was partially funded by an anonymous donation of $65,000. The original faculty of the center included Angell, Boulding, Katz, and Robert Hefner from the psychology department. The Regents appointed William Barth, a professor of adult education who had served as an editor of the Journal, as executive secretary of the new center.
During the 1960s, the center supported research, published books, organized conferences, and convened symposia where researchers presented their findings and exchanged ideas. It also participated in several large research projects, including the university's Detroit Area Study and a collaborative project on race relations with Tuskegee University.
Despite these activities, the center's future was cloudy by the late 1960s. In a 1968 Michigan Daily article, student reporter Frank Browing enumerated the center's problems: it had difficulty raising funds, its administration was often half-hearted because its staff and faculty had commitments to departments, and its lack of strong ties to a powerful department left it with very little influence within the university. These problems culminated in July 1971, when the dean of the College of Literature, Science and the Arts recommended that the center be closed. The recommendation cited the departure or retirement of influential faculty, the center's inability to attract private donations, and university-wide budget cutbacks as reasons for closing the center. Robert Hefner, the director of the center, disputed these claims, and suggested that the center's political activism was the true reason for the center's closing. Hefner was most likely referring to the center's involvement with Students for a Democratic Society and the Black Action Movement in the late 1960s and 1970. Despite the protests of some faculty and students, the center was closed in August 1971.
The records of the Center for Research on Conflict Resolution include correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, articles, papers, newspaper clippings, publications, and pamphlets. The records document the research activities of the center, and include material about international relations, peace research, conflict resolution, peace activism, and race relations.
The records are divided into 10 series: Administrative, Conferences, Correspondence, Courses, Historical, Organizations, Publications, Publicity, Research, and Topical.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for Research on Conflict Resolution.; Conflict management.
Contributors:
Boulding, Kenneth E. (Kenneth Ewart), 1910-1993; Singer, J. David (Joel David), 1925-2009
- Administrative
  The Administrative series consists of minutes, memoranda, correspondence and financial documents which relate to the administration of the center, and is arranged alphabetically by topic. The series includes the minutes and other papers of the center's executive committee.
  - Advisory Committee, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Associates of Center, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee
    - General Material
      - 1959 (Box 1)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 1)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 1)
      - 1967, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
      - Elections and Notes, 1970; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Notes and Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1959-1970; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Fellowships, undated (Box 1)
  - Financial
    - Budget
      - 1959-1964 (Box 1)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 1)
      - 1966-1971 (Box 1)
    - Funding/ Fundraising
      - 1958-1961 (Box 1)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 1)
      - 1963 (Box 1)
      - 1966-1970 (Box 1)
      - 1967 (Box 1)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
      - 1970 (Box 1)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Grants/ Funding Agencies
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1960 (Box 1)
      - Carnegie Corporation
        - Grant to Kenneth Boulding, 1962-1967 (Box 1)
        - Report, 1964 (Box 1)
        - General, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
      - Ford Foundation
        - 1963-1968 (Box 1)
        - Annual Report, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
      - Fund for Education in World Order, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Fund for Peace, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1960 (Box 1)
      - Stewart Mott Foundation, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Program, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Individual Files
    - William Barth, 1966-1971 (Box 2)
    - Gaye Crouch, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Robert Hefner
      - 1959-1963 (Box 2)
      - 1959-1966 (Box 2)
      - 1963-1969 (Box 2)
      - 1967-1971 (Box 2)
      - 1968 (Box 2)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Minorities in Planning-Housing and Urban Development, 1969 (Box 2)
- Conferences
  The Conferences series includes programs, papers, correspondence and memoranda relating to conferences that the CRCR held and also includes material from conferences that center faculty attended. The series is arranged chronologically by years.
  - Center for Research on Conflict Resolution Program Development Conference, 1959; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Symposium on the Place of Theory in the Conduct and Study of International Relations
    - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - 1960, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Zbignew Brezinski, "Communist Ideology and International Affairs,", 1960 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Conferences, 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Proposed Conferences, 1960-1962 (Box 2)
  - Strategy for Peace Conferences, 1960-1964; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Youth and Peaceful Co-Existence, Leningrad, 1960 (Box 2)
  - The Individual in Corporate Society, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Conference of Soviet and American Women, 1961 (Box 3)
  - UN Conference on Diplomatic Intercourse and Immunities, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Alternatives to the Weapons Race, 1961-1962; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - International Arms Control Symposium, 1962-1964; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Conference on Conflict Management in Organizations, 1962 (Box 3)
  - First Intercollegiate Conference on Disarmament and Arms Control, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Policy Briefing Conference, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Peace Research Institute on Civil Defense, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War Conference, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Workshop Conference; Teaching About Peace and War, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Alternative Perspectives on Vietnam, 1965 (Box 3)
  - White House Conference on International Cooperation, 1965 (Box 3)
  - International Conference on Social-Psychological Research in Developing Countries; Nigeria, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Seventh North American Peace Research Conference, 1969; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Advanced Research Projects Agency, 1970 (Box 3)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence of the center's faculty and administrative staff. The series is subdivided into three subseries: Pre-1961 Correspondence, 1961-1965 Correspondence, and Individual Correspondence. The first two subseries consist of correspondence from the period specified by their titles, and are arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. The last subseries consist of individual faculty and staff member's correspondence; it is arranged alphabetically by the name of the faculty or staff member. The Individual Correspondence subseries includes a large group of letters to and from William Barth, which are arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent.
  - Pre-1961 Correspondence-Alphabetically arranged
    - A-F, 8 folders (Box 3)
    - G-Y, 17 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence-Alphabetically Arranged, 1961-1965
    - A (Box 4)
    - Ba-Bot (Box 4)
    - Bou-Bu (Box 4)
    - Ca-Ch (Box 4)
    - Cl-Cu (Box 4)
    - D (Box 4)
    - E (Box 4)
    - Fa-Fi (Box 4)
    - Fl-Fu (Box 4)
    - Ha-Her (Box 4)
    - Hes-Hu (Box 4)
    - Ga-Gol (Box 4)
    - Gom-Gu (Box 4)
    - I-J (Box 4)
    - K (Box 4)
    - L (Box 4)
    - Mc (Box 5)
    - Ma-Mel (Box 5)
    - Men-Mi (Box 5)
    - Mo-Mu (Box 5)
    - N (Box 5)
    - O (Box 5)
    - P (Box 5)
    - R (Box 5)
    - Sa-Si (Box 5)
    - Sl-Ste (Box 5)
    - Sti-Sz (Box 5)
    - T (Box 5)
    - U-V (Box 5)
    - Y-Z (Box 5)
  - Individual Correspondence
    - Robert Angell, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - William Barth; Alphabetically Arranged
      - A, 1961-1970 (Box 5)
      - B, 1960-1970 (Box 5)
      - Elise and Kenneth Boulding, 1962-1971 (Box 5)
      - C, 1960-1966 (Box 5)
      - Jack Clareman, 1959-1963 (Box 5)
      - D-E, 1959-1970 (Box 5)
      - F, 1965-1970 (Box 5)
      - G, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
      - John Gardner, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
      - Julian Griggs, 1959-1963 (Box 5)
      - Allen Grimshaw, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
      - H, 1962-1969 (Box 5)
      - William Haber, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
      - Walter Isard, 1963-1968 (Box 6)
      - J, 1965-71 (Box 6)
      - Harold Jacobson, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
      - Phillip Jacob, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
      - Merrill Jackson, 1963-1967 (Box 6)
      - K, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
      - Herbert Kelman, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
      - L, 1966-1971 (Box 6)
      - Theodore Lentz, 1961-1968; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - M, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
      - Frederic Mosher, 1959-1964 (Box 6)
      - N, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
      - 0, 1957-1967 (Box 6)
      - P, 1960-1970 (Box 6)
      - Leslie Paffrath, 1963 (Box 6)
      - R, 1961-1967 (Box 6)
      - S, 1963-1968 (Box 6)
      - Gene Sharp, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
      - David Singer, 1960-1971 (Box 6)
      - T, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
      - Kenneth Teasdale, 1962-1967 (Box 6)
      - V, 1966 (Box 6)
      - W, 1960-1969 (Box 6)
    - Bendon Bass, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Kenneth Boulding, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
    - Robert Hefner, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Merrill Jackson
      - 1966-1969 (Box 6)
      - 1968 (Box 6)
    - Dean Pruitt, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Raymond Tanter, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - General and Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Journal of Arms Control, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Prospective Students, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - 1969, 4 folders (Box 6)
- Courses
  The Courses series includes syllabi, memoranda and other documents related to courses taught by the faculty of the center.
  - Syllabi/ Course Descriptions, 1959-1963 (Box 6)
  - Student Seminar, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Courses and Curriculum, 1967-1970 (Box 6)
  - Seminar in Jewish-Arab Relations; Joseph Ben-Dak-undated (Box 6)
  - Kenneth Boulding Seminar; bibliography, undated (Box 6)
- Historical
  The Historical series contains documents related to the founding, functioning and closing of the center, and also includes biographical material about the faculty of the center. The series consists of newspaper clippings, reports, memoranda and correspondence. It is organized chronologically by year.
  - Founding of Center for Research on Conflict Resolution, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Center for Research on Conflict Resolution; descriptive material, 1958-1961 (Box 6)
  - Clippings and Press Material re Center, 1959-1971; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Review of Center, 1959-1971; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Pamphlets, 1960-1968 (Box 7)
  - Memoranda re Future of Center, 1960-1971 (Box 7)
  - Biographical; Curricula Vitae and Staff Lists, 1963-1968 (Box 7)
  - Summaries of Center Projects, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Meeting to Redefine Center, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Office Documents, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Center Closing, 1971 (Box 7)
- Organizations
  The Organizations series consists of material related to various peace advocacy, peace research, political and academic organizations and institutions with which center faculty were involved with. It is organized alphabetically by the name of the organization or institution.
  - Fund for Education in World Order, 1967; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Institute for Arms Control and Peace Research, undated (Box 7)
  - Institute for International Order, 1958-1960; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - International Peace Research Institute, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Peace Advocacy Organizations, 1961-1965 (Box 7)
  - Peace Research and Education Project, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Peace Research Institute, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Peace Research Organizations, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Peace Research Society, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1958-1971 (Box 7)
  - Students for a Democratic Society
    - 1964, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Radical Education Project, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Universities Committee on the Problems of War and Peace, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - War Control Planners, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Washington University Research Program in International Conflict and Peace, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Wayne State University; Center for the Study of Teaching About Peace and War, 1965-1970 (Box 7)
  - Women Strike for Peace, 1964 (Box 7)
- Publications
  The Publications series consists of two subseries: Received Publications and the Journal of Conflict Resolution. The received publications subseries consists of peace advocacy and peace research journals and newsletters received by the center. The Journal of Conflict Resolution subseries consists of memoranda, minutes, and correspondence related to the administration of the Journal, which was closely associated with the center.
  - Received
    - Information from the Peace Movement of the German Democratic Republic, 1965-1967 (Box 7)
    - International Peace Research Newsletter, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Peace Publications
      - 1962-1966 (Box 7)
      - 1963 (Box 7)
    - Peace Research and Education Project Newsletter, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Peace Research News and Views, 1964-1968 (Box 7)
    - Peace Research Laboratory, 1963-1967 (Box 8)
    - Peace Research Newsletter, 1963-1964 (Box 8)
    - Peace Research Society Newsletter, 1963-1968 (Box 8)
    - Research Exchange on the Prevention of War, 1952-1956 (Box 8)
    - SANE World, 1962-1967; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues Newsletter, 1957-1968 (Box 8)
    - Student Peace Union, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Vietnam Bi-Weekly Information/ Action Report, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Win Peace and Freedom through Non-Violent Action, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Journal of Conflict Resolution
    - Establishment, 1954-1957; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - General, 1956-1962; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 8)
    - Publicity, Clippings, 1958-1962 (Box 8)
    - Special Departments, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Editorial Board Minutes, 1959-1971; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Transfer Proposal, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - Articles-Undated (Box 8)
- Publicity
  The Publicity series consists of pamphlets, advertisements, press releases, newspaper clippings and radio scripts generated to help the center publicize its work. It is organized chronologically by year.
  - Radio Series on Conflict Resolution-WUOM
    - 1959 (Box 8)
    - 1961, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1961 (Box 9)
  - Proposed Advertisements, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Recruitment/ Publicity, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Seminar Announcements, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
  - Brown Bag Publicity, undated (Box 9)
- Research
  The Research series contains material documenting the research work of the center's faculty. The series is subdivided into six subseries: Agencies Supporting Research, Articles and Papers, General Research Material, Research Projects, Proposals, and Seminars. The first subseries contains correspondence and memoranda concerning government agencies and private foundations that funded research. The Articles and Papers subseries consists of conference papers and articles intended for publication written by center faculty and associated researchers; it is organized chronologically by year. The General Research Material subseries contains memoranda and reports which discuss research methodology and logistics. The Research Projects subseries consists of correspondence, reports, memoranda and articles concerning large, collaborative projects such as the Detroit Area Study and the joint projects with Tuskegee University. The Proposals subseries consists of research proposals written by center faculty or associated researchers for submission to funding agencies. It is organized into two groupings: proposals arranged alphabetically by the name of the researcher, and proposals organized chronologically by year. These two systems of filing were probably maintained by different members of the center's faculty or staff. Proposals might be in either grouping, and researchers looking for a particular researcher or proposal should look in both places. The Seminars subseries contains papers and minutes from research seminars where faculty shared their research findings.
  - Agencies Supporting Research
    - Institute of Science and Technology, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Canadian Peace Research Institute, 1961-1969 (Box 9)
    - U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1962-1969; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Articles and Papers
    - 1951-1964, undated (Box 9)
    - Robert Angell-Notes from a Visit to the Soviet Union, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Elise Boulding-"The Technology of Peace-Making,", 1961 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Publications, 1961-1967 (Box 9)
    - J. David Singer-The Uses of Threat, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Merrill Jackson, 1963-1969 (Box 9)
    - 1963 (Box 9)
    - John Robinson-Attitude Measurement, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Judith Long, 1963 (Box 9)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 9)
    - Kenneth Boulding-1963-1965, undated (Box 9)
    - Dean Pruitt, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Clinton Fink, 1964-1967 (Box 9)
    - Thomas Hayden, "Radical Nomad,", 1964 (Box 9)
    - Robert Rosenthal, "On the Goals of Education,", 1964 (Box 9)
    - J.D. Singer and Melvin Small, "Formal Alliances,", 1965 (Box 9)
    - Jacques Bude, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Clinton Fink, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    - Clinton Fink, 1966-1969 (Box 10)
    - John Delamater; dissertation proposal, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Irwin Katz, Thomas Henchy and Harvey Allen, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Kenneth Boulding, 1967; undated (Box 10)
    - Summary of Faculty Research Projects and Publications, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Raymond Tanter, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Martin Patchen, 1968 (Box 10)
    - William Gamson, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Elizabeth Converse, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Clinton Fink, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Gaye Crouch, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Roger Geiger, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Klaus Riegel, 1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - John Delamater, undated (Box 10)
    - John Robinson and Solomon Jacobsen, undated (Box 10)
  - General Research Material
    - General Research Material
      - 1958-1959 (Box 10)
      - Undated (Box 10)
    - Questionnaires and Statistics/ Methodology, undated (Box 10)
  - Research Projects
    - Ann Arbor Survey, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Arab Refugee Project, undated (Box 10)
    - Project Camelot, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - Church-University Co-operative Program on Social Change, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
    - Detroit Area Study
      - 1956-1965 (Box 10)
      - 1961-1965 (Box 10)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Guidebook, 1964 (Box 10)
      - Funding, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Tuskegee Project
      - 1964-1966 (Box 10)
      - 1967 (Box 10)
      - 1969 (Box 10)
    - Alphabetical by Researcher
      - A, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
      - B, 1958-1963 (Box 10)
      - Elise Boulding, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
      - Kenneth Boulding, 1964; undated (Box 11)
      - C, 1960-1967 (Box 11)
      - D-E, 1961-1963 (Box 11)
      - F, 1966 (Box 11)
      - Clinton Fink
        - 1960-1963 (Box 11)
        - 1965-1971 (Box 11)
        - 1966 (Box 11)
        - 1966-1971 (Box 11)
        - 1968 (Box 11)
        - Women in the Workplace, 1971 (Box 11)
      - G, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
      - H, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
      - Robert Hefner, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
      - H-K, 1959-1966 (Box 11)
      - I-K, circa 1963 (Box 11)
      - L, 1959-1961; undated (Box 11)
      - M, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
      - N-O, 1959-1963 (Box 11)
      - O-P, 1960-1962 (Box 11)
      - R, 1959-1965; undated (Box 11)
      - S, 1959-1967 (Box 11)
      - T-Z, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
    - Chronological
      - 1959-1960 (Box 11)
      - 1960-1962 (Box 11)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 11)
      - 1960, undated (Box 11)
      - Proposal to Ford Foundation, 1961 (Box 12)
      - Proposal to Carnegie Corporation, 1961-1964 (Box 12)
      - Office of Research Administration; Proposals, 1963-1966 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1963; undated (Box 12)
      - Proposal to National Institute of Health, 1964 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1964-1967 (Box 12)
      - Social Psychological Research in Developing Countries, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Center Study of Foreign Aid, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Robert Hefner and Sheldon Levy, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Bendix Corporation Proposal, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Center Proposal to American Jewish Committee, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Synopses of Research Proposals on Arms Control and Disarmament, 1966 (Box 12)
      - Interdisciplinary Summer Institute on International Relations, 1966-1969; 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Kenneth Boulding, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
      - Proposal to National Science Foundation, William Gamson, 1967 (Box 12)
      - Robert Hefner Proposal to Advanced Research Projects Agency, 1967 (Box 12)
      - Detroit Projects
        - Urban Community Resources, Incorporated, 1967-1968; 3 folders (Box 12)
        - Inner-City Organizing Committee, 1968 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1967-1971 (Box 12)
      - Qualitative International Archive, 1968; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Ernest Harburg, 1968 (Box 12)
      - "Theory Group", 1968-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - "Radical Thinking,", 1968 (Box 12)
      - Housing and Urban Development Proposal, 1968 (Box 12)